PAOLO ALBERTO DR. VELASCO

34 years old; Married; CP#: +63 917 800-2095; Email: paolov1ph@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://paolov1ph.github.io/portfolio/

OBJECTIVE

I aim to grow my career in a well-established organization that will fully utilize my team management, supervision and technical skills for mutual growth and success. I firmly believe that my unique skillset and work experience in project and people management, software development, actuarial finance and pension administration will be a big advantage to your company.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Chanz IT Solutions Inc.

Software Engineer, 2020

- Designs websites and systems based on clients' requirements and preferences.
- CMS and CRM integration for websites.
- Adds/Improves features to company's websites.

Cid Systems Inc.

Developer Team Lead, 2018 to 2019

- Developed and maintained features of the company's accounting software system.
- Managed code updates to git repositories based on client contract requirements.
- Lead and managed web development projects of a team of developers.
- Designed websites and systems based on clients' requirements and preferences.
- Tasked to interview junior web developer and QA applicants for hiring.
- Identified process and workflow improvements for development team.
- Planned, managed and scheduled tasks/workload for development team.
- Provided additional OA support and created and validated test cases based on system requirement.

Willis Towers Watson, Global Processing and Technology Center

IT Business Analyst – Tester & Quality Assurance, 2017 to 2018

- Created testing plans for company in-house system for data management.
- Identified points of improvement for company systems and tools.
- Provided system support for the global health and group benefits configuration team.

Pension Administration – Team Leader & Developer, 2014 to 2017

- Managed Philippine-based developer support team for United States Pension Administration Group.
- Developed programs for company systems for pension administration, calculations and forms
- Developed Bulk Lump Sum (BLS) and Pension Plan termination projects for United States
- Supervised the updating of employee databases to meet service level agreements for American & Canadian clients
- Provided programming set-up and support database updates for company in-house systems

<u>Major Accomplishment:</u> Played a key role in the creation & set-up of a new team by developing and implementing BLS processes & procedures, defining manpower requirements, hiring & actual operational start.

Actuarial Valuation - Actuarial Analyst, 2009 to 2014

- · Performed accounting & funding valuations & projections for Defined Benefit (DB) & hybrid pension plans
- · Provided programming set-up and support for pension plans for company in-house systems
- Provided administrative support for Defined Contribution (DC) benefit calculation
- Managed and supervised group plan valuations and benefit calculation projects

CERTIFICATION/EDUCATION

Web DevelopmentZuitt Philippines Inc., Intensive Coding Boot Camp, Timog Avenue, Quezon City, 2018 **Java Programming 1 & 2**UPSITF, University of the Philippines, Diliman, Quezon City, 2018

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

College Bachelor of Science in Mathematics Major in Actuarial Science, 2004-2008

University of Santo Tomas Manila, College of Science

Secondary & Primary Xavier High School, 2000-2004; Xavier Grade School, 1993-2000

PROFESSIONAL TRAININGS & SEMINARS

- 7 Habits for Managers; Towers Watson, Taguig City, Philippines; November 2016
- Project Management Training; Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia; July 2014
- Benefit Optimization: Building the organization's right benefits program; WTW Regional Training, China; February 2013
- · Benefits Design Training; Towers Watson Regional Training, Shanghai, China; February 2013
- 7 Habits of Highly Effective People; Towers Watson, Taguig City, Philippines 2012
- Assertive Communication; Towers Watson, Taguig City, Philippines; 2010

SKILLS

- Effective and efficient supervisory and management skills, people management and project management
- Proficient in web development and programming languages HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, MySOL, Java, ¡Query, VB and Fortran.
- Proficient in web development frameworks and libraries Laravel, Prestashop, VueJS, Bootstrap.
- Proficient in MS Office Applications.
- Excellent knowledge of pension and retirement plans in USA, Canada, Hong Kong, Korea, Taiwan, Sweden and Philippines
- Excellent knowledge of pension accounting, financial mathematics and annuities
- Excellent oral and written communication skills
- Solution-oriented, has good leadership and time management skills and best in finishing deadlines

REFERENCES *(number available upon request)

